MAZIN **ABODI**

211th SE Ave SE, Kent, WA 98031 | H: 551-998-2416 | mazinalobodi@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Telecom engineer, with 5 years experience in telecom and IT, End User support, Help Desk. Familiar with IT infrastructure and telecom systems 2G, GSM, 3G and UMTS. Have passion about IT & telecom fields. I am seeking to leverage my professional and educational background into a role with a progressive organization.

EXPERIENCE

02/2017 to 09/2018 Business Developments Engineer Set Solution Company — Khartoum, Sudan

- Built trusting, positive and productive internal and external professional relationships with clients while maintaining existing customer relationship
- Prepared effective proposals, presentations, demonstrations and sales tool on business development opportunities for management
- Oversaw sale operations, analyzed costs, and negotiated tender/contracts terms
- Generated new business through client consultant and subcontractor referrals for services. Created effective marketing, sales and other promotional initiatives
- Developed and integrated market plans to efficiently position the company brand within targeted markets

02/2016 to 12/2016 Network Operation Center Engineer

Morgan Group for IT and Communication Technologies – Khartoum, Sudan

- Sites monitoring and reporting using Nagos software (Shifting 24/7)
- Receiving and reporting customers and subscribers complaints
- Providing first line support and Log and archive all technical issues
- Escalated of unsolved issues to second line support engineers
- Reporting required field activities to maintenance teams
- Update operators with critical alarms, prepared daily and weekly sites status reports

02/2014 to 11/2015 Telecom Site Engineer Takhatobtele Telecommunication Company — Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

- Performed site survey for Customer and Mobily BTSs and preparation reports
- Installed/configure the Microwave links (indoor, outdoor units, cabling and antennas alignment) between customer and Mobily BTSs site
- Perform E2E and UAT tests (software/hardware) for the microwave links
- Delivered RFS (Ready for Service) reports
- Coordination between customer and operator, provide 2nd line supports to other teams also provided solutions for the site's technical issues
- Prepared and presented technical proposals for clients

06/2011 to 12/2013 Telecom & IT Engineer Sudanese Electricity Distribution Company — Khartoum, Sudan

- Help desk activities (windows installation & maintenance) and network support and IP telephony network systems. Install, configure, and maintain network equipment (routers, switches, cabling)
- Provided technical support to more the 100 users, and assisted with application related issues including lodging and connectivity error as well as basic application.
- Logged IT related tickets like incidents and service request from end users
- Supported company employees (users) through various tools and software such as remote desktop connection and handle up to 25 requests per day
- Supported continuous improvement initiatives in business processes through technology.
- Provided 24/7 technical phone support while monitoring critical applications and hardware
- Installing and maintenance common types of printers (HP LaserJet, Globalis)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Telecom Engineering Future University

COURSES

- 3G Mobile Networks Planning
- Project Management Professional
- Telecom Transmission Technologies & Radio
 Planning (3G, GSM, 2G)
- Cisco Certificate Network Associate (CCNA)

SKILLS

- Adept in customer service and problem solving
- Systems Windows (XP, 7, 8, 10) Mac Basics
- Networking LAN, TCP/IP, etc
 - Hardware Laptops,
 Desktops, Mobile Phones (iPhone), printers, etc
 - Ticketing system Service Now, HP, Iris, Manage Engine

TRAINING

Attended training in IT at Bank of Khartoum, Khartoum – Sudan

LANGAUGE

- English
- German
- Arabic